# Kento Katsumata

kentokatsumata@keio.jp
https://kenty.io
080-5541-7178

Tokyo, Setagaya 1-31-1-206 Kaminoge

Second-year master student with 4 years of solid working experience as an intern at a leading edtech company. Strong track record in project leadership, idea generation, managing multiple responsibilities, and problem solving. Good interpersonal, analytical, and organizational skills. Native speaker of English and Japanese. Expertise lies in ubiquitous computing, HCI, networking, and machine learning.



### EDUCATION



#### MASTER OF MEDIA AND GOVERNANCE

Keio University | 2020/09 ~ 2022/09 (Expected)

- Cyber Informatics Program
- Member of Jin Nakazawa/Jun Murai Lab

# B.A. ENVIRONMENTAL INFORMATION Keio University | 2016/09 ~ 2020/09

- Member of Jin Nakazawa/Jun Murai Lab
- Leader of Computing for Human Well-being Research Group



# AWARD

# FINALIST & AWARD OF EXCELLENCE

SPAJAM Hackathon 2020

# FIRST PLACE Smart Hackathon by ZENRIN 2019



## COURSE WORK

The Internet, Heuristic Computing, Object Oriented Programming, Statistics Database, Ubiquitous System Architecture, Data Acquisition, Database Architecture, Emergence of Data Driven Society and Strategy by Yahoo!, Design Research, Design Programming, Information Law, Beyond Blockchain



# **EXPERIENCE**



### APP DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

#### Yahoo Japan Corporation | 2020/09 ~ 2020/10

- Collaborated with the engineering team members to develop new bookmark feature for Yahoo! Japan app
- Created and implemented log schema for future analytics

#### LAUNCHING TEAM MEMBER / SENIOR INSTRUCTOR / SERVICE LEADER

#### Life is Tech USA, Inc. | 2019/04 ~ Present

- Worked jointly with a team of 6 members and developed and launched "Disney Codeillusion" (https://codeillusion.io), an online coding tutorial game, in USA
- Designed and spearheaded challenging and engaging lesson plans for students
- Analyzed feedback to improve service standards and received high customer satisfaction rating (4 out of 5 stars)

#### MENTOR (INSTRUCTOR)/ Web Service Course Curriculum Director

#### Life is Tech, Inc. | 2017/05 ~ Present

- Taught IOS, Unity, Web design, Video Editing, and Digital Music to 500+ middle and high school students
- Motivated students to develop creative and innovative thinking skills through coding and team building activities
- Organized and run IT summer camps abroad at University of Oxford and National University of Singapore
- Instructed 30+ young mentors on technical skills and performance management



# **PUBLICATION** -

**K.Katsumata**, Y.Noda, N.Isokawa, S.Katayama, T.Okoshi and J.Nakazawa, "SleepThermo: The affect of in-cloth monitored body temperature change during sleep on human well-being." in Proceedings of The 2019 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing Adjunct Publication – UbiComp '19 United Kingdom, London Adjunct, 2019, pp. 1602–1607

**K.Katsumata**, Y.Eigen, Y.Noda, M.Tsuruoka, S.Hashiba, S.Numoto, S.Katayama, T.Okoshi, and J.Nakazawa, "Motivating Long-term Dietary Habit Modification through Mobile MR Gamification" In Proceedings of the 17th Annual International Conference on Mobile Systems, Applications, and Services (MobiSys '19 South Korea, Seoul). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 671-672.